<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Urban Futures</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/</link><atom:link href="https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Urban Futures</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/media/icon_hu5486d42984c30aaff6be99d37062b147_3155_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Urban Futures</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/</link></image><item><title>People</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/people/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Data and Methods</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/data/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="faculty-data">Faculty Data&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Data for USC Price faculty will be gathered from the &lt;a href="https://priceschool.usc.edu/faculty/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Price faculty page&lt;/a>&lt;br>
We can obtain name, contact, position, expertise, degrees, and a biological sketch of each professor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="google-scholar-pages">Google Scholar Pages&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most faculty have a Google Scholar Page, where we can pull data relating to each faculty&amp;rsquo;s research publications.
Each publication has a title, authors, year, and number of citations, as well as a vast pool of textual data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="extraction-methods">Extraction Methods&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Using Python with Google Colab notebooks, we generated a web-scraping script that obtained the necessary information.
The package BeautifulSoup provided a framework for obtaining data from each webpage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information for faculty and their publications were stored in dictionaries as key:value pairs and connected by faculty name as the primary key.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Extracting data from the text of publications proved to be a difficult task, one we did not complete during the scope of this semester.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using spaCy, we were able to generate named entity recognitions and successfully fetch the dataset names using custom rules of finding organizations (example: JULIET clinical trial). However, the variation among the format of publications yielded poor model training results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Problem</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/problem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/problem/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-motivation">Project Motivation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the dynamic landscape of urban planning, we face a significant challenge—the absence of a centralized data hub for research. The multifaceted nature of urban environments, with their economic, social, and environmental intricacies, demands a comprehensive approach. However, the current disarray in urban research impedes our ability to efficiently tackle these complexities. The scattered nature of data sources, combined with a lack of a cohesive framework, limits our capacity for informed decision-making in urban planning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without a unified platform, we grapple with inefficient problem-solving. Disorganized urban research not only hinders the extraction of valuable insights but also obstructs the collaboration necessary for effective solutions. Urban challenges require a collective effort, yet collaboration remains uncommon due to the disparate nature of research endeavors. This fragmentation prevents us from fully understanding and addressing the nuanced needs of urban environments, hindering our potential to develop sustainable and impactful solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we delve into &amp;ldquo;The Problem,&amp;rdquo; our mission is clear: establish a centralized knowledge hub that transcends these challenges, enabling us to make more informed decisions, foster collaboration, and unlock the full potential of urban planning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Results</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/results/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/results/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page contains key sections of the &lt;strong>Final Report&lt;/strong> for the project focused on results to date. It should be no more than 2 pages long. An initial draft can be created at any point during the project, and can be refined as the project progresses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="system-and-model-performance">System and Model Performance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Show the performance of the best system and model(s) developed, showing clearly the performance metrics and improvements over the baseline system as appropriate. Create visualizations that show clearly these results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="discussion-of-findings">Discussion of Findings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Offer a discussion of the main findings using the system developed. Put the results in the context of the original problem statement and the questions that were posed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discuss any unexpected results, and potential explanations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enumerate (ideally in bullets) the most important findings, and their impact on your project goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="limitations-and-future-work">Limitations and Future Work&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discuss any limitations of the work to date, how these limitations could be addressed in future work. Discuss what lines of work are most promising given the understanding of the problem and the data gained throughout the project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goals</title><link>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckids-datafest.github.io/2023-fall-urban-futures/goals/</guid><description>&lt;p>The goal is to create a &lt;b>research networking tool&lt;/b> that allows researchers and decision-makers to access centralized research information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-web-application">A Web Application&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our first goal was to create a responsive web app to display relevant data we have collected. For this specific project, fancy charts and visualizations were not necessary as we simply displayed data tables; in future development, we intend to add more robust data visualization techniques to help users grasp key ideas, concepts, and trends in research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The web-app was developed with Next.js for the front-end and Node.js supporting the backend with server-side rendering, ensuring high performance even as we scale. The Vite framework was utlized to complement reactjs in development.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>